<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!--

   Copyright 2010 OpenEngSB Division, Vienna University of Technology

   Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
   you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
   You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
   distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
   limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter id="pluginArchetype" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>How to use the Maven archetype to create a YASTE plugin</title>
  <para>
    This section describes how a new YASTE plugin can be created using a Maven archetype.
  </para>
  <section>
    <title>Using the archetype</title>
    <para>
      The following command is used to start the project generation:
      <programlisting>
        <![CDATA[
   mvn archetype:generate -DarchetypeCatalog="http://maven.openengsb.org/archetypes/"
        ]]>
      </programlisting>
      The archetype named connector-archetype should show up in the archetype list.
      Select the archetype connector-archetype. Maven will ask if the default values for the properties shall be used. Type 'n' to overwrite the default values.
      The following properties are needed to generate a connector project:
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>artifactId: The artifactId of the generated wrapper project for the service-engine and the service-unit.</listitem>
        <listitem>groupId: The groupId of the generated wrapper project. Should be org.openengsb.</listitem>
        <listitem>version: The version of the generated wrapper project.</listitem>
        <listitem>se-artifactId: The artifactId of the service-engine.</listitem>
        <listitem>su-artifactId: The artifactId of the service-unit.</listitem>
        <listitem>description: The description of the tool connector.</listitem>
        <listitem>namespace: The namespace of the tool connector.</listitem>
        <listitem>package: The package for the source code of the service-engine.</listitem>
        <listitem>connector-name: The connector name. This is used as prefix for Java classes so it should start with a upper-case letter.</listitem>
        <listitem>domain-package: The package where the domain interface can be found which is implemented by this tool connector.</listitem>
        <listitem>domain-name: The interface name of the domain interface that is implemented by this tool connector.</listitem>
        <listitem>urn: The URN that will be used to address this tool connector.</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>

